Guide to the Sallie Bingham Collection of Lefroy, Caperton, and Montague Family Papers, 1866-1959 and undated RL.11104
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham collection of Lefroy, Caperton, and Montague family papers
1866-1959 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bingham, Sallie
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.11104
0.8 Linear Feet
Family papers documenting the Lefroy, Caperton, and Montague familes, representing the families in Sallie Bingham's matrilineal line. These materials belonged to Sallie Bingham's mother, Mary Caperton Bingham, until her death, when they went to Sallie; her sister, Eleanor Bingham Miller; and their niece, Emily Bingham. Two figures documented in these papers, Helena Lefroy Caperton and Sallie Montague Lefroy, are the focus, along with her mother, of Sallie Bingham’s 2014 book, The Blue Box. Includes genealogies, letters, wills, a bill of sale, short stories and other writing, speeches, a prayer book, list, a few clippings, and Irish and English postcards.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by family.
Biographical / Historical
Sallie Bingham (born January 22, 1937) is an American author, playwright, poet, teacher, feminist activist, and philanthropist.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sallie Bingham Collection of Lefroy, Caperton, and Montague Family Papers, 1866-1959 and undated, were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
See also the Sallie Bingham Papers.
Collection Overview
Family papers documenting the Lefroy, Caperton, and Montague familes, representing the families in Sallie Bingham's matrilineal line. These materials belonged to Sallie Bingham's mother, Mary Caperton Bingham, until her death, when they went to Sallie; her sister, Eleanor Bingham Miller; and their niece, Emily Bingham. Two figures documented in these papers, Helena Lefroy Caperton and Sallie Montague Lefroy, are the focus, along with her mother, of Sallie Bingham’s 2014 book, The Blue Box. Includes genealogies, letters, wills, a bill of sale, short stories and other writing, speeches, a prayer book, list, a few clippings, and Irish and English postcards. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Genealogies (histories); Wills; Receipts (financial records); Speeches; Short stories; Prayer-books; Bingham, Sallie; Bingham, Sallie; Bingham, Sallie -- Blue box; Bingham, Sallie -- Family; Caperton, Helena Lefroy, 1878-1962; LeFroy, Sallie Montague, 1850-1942; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Lefroy papers
  Scope and Contents
  Series includes a few Lefroy family letters, a will for Dean Lefroy, and a list of Lefroys serving in World War I. However, primarily contains essays, speeches, and other writings by Sallie Montague Lefroy. Also includes her prayer book.
  - Aunt Mary Lefroy letters to Helena Lefroy Caperton, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dean Lefroy will, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jeffry Arthur Lefroy letter, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lefroys in World War I, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy essay on Irish monasticism, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy essays, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy introductions made at the Richmond Women's Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy prayerbook, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy speech on Adlai Stevenson, around 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sallie Montague Lefroy speech on Pocahontas, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sallie Watson Montague Lefroy's AUTUMN GARNER, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Caperton papers
  Series contains material related to Helena Lafroy Caperton, including writings, letters, a will, a mortgage check, as well as poems she collected. There is also genealogical information, and letters for Clifford Caperton.
  - Clifford Caperton school letters, 1888-1889 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gignilliat connection letter on Caperton-Stiles link, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Helena Lefroy Caperton's CAPTAIN MARY GREEN, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Helena Lefroy Caperton letters, 1943-1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Helena Lefroy Caperton mortgage check, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Helena Lefroy Caperton will, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Helena Lefroy Caperton writings, 1955 and undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. W. Gaston Caperton letters, 1929-1930 and undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pelot-Nephew-Stiles genealogy, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Poems Helena Lefroy Caperton saved, 1941 and undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sallie Bingham letters to Helena Lefroy Caperton, 1949-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Montague papers
  Series primarily features Montague family genealogical information. There is also material related to Melinda Fox Montague, including letters and a will. Also present is John Montague's 1866 bill of sale for cotton.
  - Hanson letter re: Earl of Egremont, 1905 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Helen Montague biography and genealogy, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Howland/Montague genealogy, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - John Montague bill of sale, 1866 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lord Percival letter to Melinda Fox Montague, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Melinda Fox Montague correspondence with daughter Sallie Montague Lefroy, 1877-1878 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Melinda Fox Montague/ Fox family, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Melinda Fox Montague will, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous papers
  Includes undated English and Irish postcards.
  - English and Irish postcards, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)